Phi!
I'll create a kingdom where you
and your family can live in peace!
I promise!
It's a charm.
Relie taught me it.
She said it makes sure
we'll see each other again.
Phi...
Well, excuse me!
Did I interrupt something?
Sorry to intrude, my prince.
Fight for the sky
afuredasu kanjou mou tomaranai
I can't stop the overflowing emotions
mune ni idaitai bokura no gensou
The illusions we hold so dear
Just revolution
kienai aza ni obiete ite mo
Fear of the scar that won't disappear
toki ga mujou ni sugiteku dake
Won't stop the ruthless passage of time
susumeyo aru ga mama
Go forth, the way you are
Let's burst up!
ima koso kawaru toki
Now is the time for change
Let's boost up!
kakumei no kane no ne ga
The sound of the bell of revolution
doko made mo hibiite yuku
Resounds far and wide
To be the soldier
mou koko ni wa irarenai
We can't stay here any longer
To be the soldier
kaze wo kitte yuke ikite yuke
Cut through the wind, live your life
hiryuu no gotoku
Like a flying dragon
hajimari ga michiru mama densetsu ni nare
As the beginning draws near, become a legend
tokihanatte yuke tonde yuke
Release yourself, fly ahead
inochi wo tagirasete
Overflow with life
erabareshi mono wo matsu sekai wa owari da New age
The world that waits for a chosen one is over! New age!
m 630.08 484.75 b 633.42 480.43 633.37 467.41 629.93 463.57 632.98 463.52 635.42 459.26 638.32 463.63 645.2 459.98 646.66 460.07 651.44 464.46 653.13 463.47 654.7 462.22 656.5 461.57 660.86 459.97 664.66 462.18 665.24 466.8 665.69 470.41 665.43 474.11 665.71 477.76 665.89 480.03 666.5 482.27 667 485 666.01 485 664.42 485 662.84 485 661.39 485 659.94 485 658.62 485 661.48 478.48 660.39 472.1 659.7 465.82 659.6 465 657.41 463.54 656.86 463.8 655.05 464.67 652.25 466.09 652.16 467.46 651.75 473.2 650.06 479.2 653.77 484.83 650.61 484.83 647.66 484.83 644.66 484.83 647.69 478.69 646.12 472.33 645.93 466.1 645.9 465.27 643.87 463.65 643.28 463.85 641.53 464.46 638.87 465.58 638.63 466.88 637.52 472.77 636.85 478.8 639.45 484.75 636.71 484.75 633.63 484.75 630.08 484.75 m 553.93 484.4 b 559.09 480.63 559.26 455.51 554.34 451.12 560.64 451.12 566.73 450.71 572.74 451.26 577.24 451.67 579.68 455.14 579.88 459.61 580.08 464.02 578.13 467.52 573.72 468.79 570.57 469.69 567.2 469.87 563.86 470.38 562.05 478.58 562.78 481.77 568.27 484.4 562.89 484.4 558.7 484.4 553.93 484.4 m 563.54 468.63 b 567.21 467.03 571 466.46 572.74 464.27 574.15 462.52 574.19 457.92 572.81 456.15 571.1 453.94 567.31 453.34 563.54 451.64 563.54 457.77 563.54 462.18 563.54 468.63 m 626.34 473.49 b 626.29 481.53 622.52 485.56 615.08 485.55 607.56 485.54 603.64 481.19 603.74 472.95 603.83 465.28 608.07 460.95 615.36 461.08 622.61 461.21 626.39 465.48 626.34 473.49 m 608.95 472.92 b 609.35 475.18 609.22 477.74 610.29 479.62 611.27 481.34 613.58 483.41 615.22 483.34 616.9 483.28 619.01 481.08 619.95 479.3 620.89 477.53 620.82 475.12 620.82 472.99 620.85 466.41 618.84 463.06 615.1 463.02 611.29 462.98 609.31 466.31 608.95 472.92 m 724.76 481.07 b 723.22 484.78 718.4 486.73 712.71 484.98 707.31 483.33 704.41 477.15 705.74 470.19 706.9 464.16 711.18 460.68 716.91 461.1 722.64 461.52 725.75 465.52 725.88 473.04 721.11 473.04 716.35 473.04 709.73 473.04 711.8 476.95 712.68 481.29 714.96 482.22 717.7 483.34 721.62 481.55 724.76 481.07 m 720.86 470.93 b 720.18 467.09 720.47 462.83 715.79 463.2 711.72 463.52 711.26 467.22 711.33 470.93 714.48 470.93 717.39 470.93 720.86 470.93 m 684.31 479.16 b 687.28 480.83 689.68 482.65 692.38 483.45 693.42 483.76 695.9 481.98 696.34 480.69 696.73 479.54 695.57 477.29 694.43 476.32 692.44 474.63 689.58 473.89 687.75 472.08 686.29 470.64 684.85 468.01 685.18 466.25 685.51 464.5 687.86 462.79 689.72 461.79 691.19 460.99 693.26 461.14 695.07 461.14 698.95 461.15 701.38 462.62 700.43 467.07 698.44 465.69 696.65 463.85 694.51 463.21 693.35 462.87 691.58 464.58 690.09 465.36 690.89 466.67 691.41 468.33 692.54 469.21 694.48 470.71 697.25 471.32 698.85 473.06 700.46 474.82 702.21 477.71 701.82 479.7 701.42 481.72 698.76 484 696.59 484.78 694.11 485.68 691.06 485.24 688.28 485.06 683.82 484.76 684.78 481.3 684.31 479.16 m 583.55 463.58 b 586.17 464.37 588.75 458.99 591.49 463.52 591.51 463.55 593.22 462.13 594.12 462.15 596.33 462.22 598.56 462.63 600.69 463.23 600.91 463.29 600.53 465.52 600.43 466.74 599.45 466.42 598.02 466.39 597.57 465.71 594.98 461.78 592.49 464.76 592.22 466.56 591.45 471.69 591.62 476.96 591.69 482.18 591.69 482.85 593.21 483.5 594.73 484.72 590.44 484.72 587.05 484.72 583.7 484.72 587.09 479.76 587.01 467.36 583.55 463.58 m 670.24 484.8 b 674.57 480.87 674.59 467.22 670.84 463.58 673.27 462.86 675.59 462.17 678.36 461.34 678.83 469.29 679.28 477 679.74 484.8 677.8 484.8 674.37 484.8 670.24 484.8 m 680.27 455.15 b 678.28 456.6 677 458.24 675.93 458.11 674.86 457.98 673.25 456.08 673.26 454.96 673.27 453.9 675.02 452.07 676.08 452.02 677.18 451.96 678.37 453.63 680.27 455.15
We managed to take care of this one.
Let's meet up with Celes and company.
This is odd.
Odd? What's wrong?
Everything.
From the moment we started this
training camp, nothing's made any sense.
I'm surprised.
You're sharper than I thought you were.
And here I thought all you have in your head
are Machine Dragons and Lux.
Yeah. Every now and then I can be pretty—
Hey! Don't make fun of me!
Miss Lisha? Krulcifer?
Airi?
We took care of the Diablos.
Are you all right?
Yes. We managed to repel the attacks too.
However, Shalice and Tillfur's Machine Dragons
were damaged and they can't fight.
This sucks...
Yes.
Don't give me "Yes"!
Also, we found the entrance to the lowest level,
Yes.
Is that the only thing you can say?!
but according to La Krulshe,
the presence of some kind of key is required.
Yes.
Stop with the one word answers!
What could that be?
If you say that again,
we'll start just saying "Oh, no!"
Oh, good idea!
Come on! Say it!
We have no choice but to
retreat for the time being.
Yes.
Oh, no!
This is no time to be fooling around!
What are you doing here?!
Easy, there.
If you kill me, that female dies too.
What does that mean?
She has one of these planted in her.
One of the Ragnarok seeds I've been growing.
What?!
When you plant one into a living being,
it eats them from the inside
and turns them into an Abyss.
Then they become a faithful servant of the Ragnarok, unable to defy its will.
By the looks of it, this one has been defying the orders
and suffering constant fever and headaches.
Orders?
I had the Ragnarok give that order.
The order to kill you, Lux Arcadia!
Defying the order means suffering a living hell,
eventually turning to dust and dying.
So how much longer do you plan on waving that thing in my face?
Let's make a deal.
As things stand, the girl has only several days left to live.
What?
So here's my offer.
I'll use this to make the Ragnarok give an order to save the girl,
and you open the door of the ruin floating outside for me.
What door?
A key is necessary to open the door to the lowest level.
Use that key girl of yours.
You have two days.
Don't drag your feet.
Wait!
Who are you?!
Were you wondering why I have the same hair color as you and your siblings?
I'm the real deal.
Unlike you lot.
What should I do?
Lu.
Phi.
I'm hungry.
I see. You don't remember anything.
Did I cause any problems?
Not at all.
How is it?
Good.
You too, Lu. Open wide.
N-No. I'm not hungry.
Open wide.
I told you...
Okay, fine.
What's wrong?
Nothing. Don't worry about it.
Why?!
Philuffy was supposed to
have been saved back then!
Why?!
I remembered.
It hasn't been seven years since I last saw Philuffy.
We met was five years ago, on this island.
You rescued Philuffy when the former empire had kidnapped her for human experimentation.
But Philuffy was already dead.
What? No!
That's not possible!
She's alive right now!
Yes. She woke up.
She was much tougher and stronger than before.
It was when I because headmistress of this school
that I found out Philuffy had turned into an Abyss.
An Abyss?
I have to go into the ruins.
With the technology from them,
I may be able to save Philuffy.
Is that why you brought us to this island?
She's running out of time.
I must reach the lowest level and find a way to save her.
Even if it means giving up my own life.
Phi.
Why?
Why are you visiting my mother's grave?
Just leave me alone.
This is supposed to cheer you up.
My mother does it for me.
Lux.
Hey! Lux!
Lux!
He's finally awake.
Quit daydreaming already!
We've been tuning Bahamut for you
all morning, you know!
I-I'm sorry.
So, are we done now?
Yes. If I send you the release code,
you can use the Over Limit.
I'll go get permission to use it
from the headmistress.
Hopefully the day you'll need to use it never comes.
It's been a while, Lux,
the weakest hero, who sacrificed himself
and suffered defeat for his ideals.
That voice...
Is that you?!
Fugil Arcadia?!
Where are you?!
You know, I find the melody of the horn
Hayes had quite displeasing.
Don't you feel the same way?
What do you know?
If you want to save your childhood friend,
the only way is to destroy the horn and
defeat the Ragnarok controlling the seed.
Naturally, it's up to you whether you trust this information.
By the way, I have a question for you.
Phi!
You have to stay in bed!
I know.
I know that there's an Abyss inside of me.
Huh?
But it's okay, I guess.
After mom got sick and died,
Relie was so sad and lonely.
So I decided I can't afford to die.
You're sad and lonely too.
But it's okay now.
Now you have many people
who care about you.
And Relie won't be lonely with you around.
Phi...
You've become strong,
so it's all going to be okay.
No!
I can't do anything.
I'm still weak.
On that day...
Because you saved me...
Because you've been there for me...
I was able to fight.
So don't leave me!
I'll save you for real this time!
I see.
You haven't changed.
Thank you.
I'll wait for you.
I'm happy to have you all back here so soon!
What is the key we need to proceed?
I'm sorry, but I cannot tell you that.
I see.
Very well, then.
Everyone, stand back!
I'll break the door with Seven Heads!
What?!
P-Please don't do that!
Krulcifer.
I understand.
It's okay. Leave it to me.
The door opened just like that!
Krulcifer, who are you?
I was the first one to meet La Krulshe,
so I was simply recognized as her master.
Right?
Um...
I see.
Krulcifer is so refined.
Unlike a certain princess who tries to solve everything with force.
I see.
Anyway, let's proceed ahead.
So this is the lowest level.
It doesn't look like the kind of place we'd find
Machine Dragons or ancient documents.
This is the right place, isn't it?
This is the right place.
I have successfully restored the memories I had lost.
I remember everything.
What I must do is...
wipe out every single one of you.
The clan that betrayed my masters,
and everyone like them.
La Krulshe!
What are you—
Thank you, my prince!
Hayes!
You foolishly did exactly as planned.
Thanks to you, I had no trouble getting in.
Phi!
Why is she here?!
If I give a strong enough order, there will be
no room for defiance. She has to obey.
Fools!
This is an order, monster girl!
Kill them all!
Bahamut!
Airi, Headmistress, stay close to me.
I won't allow you to raise a hand against my master!
Unmanned Machine Dragons?!
How are they so quick?!
This isn't how a Wyvern normally moves.
Could that be... Over Limit?!
I'll pin her down!
Celes!
Why, you!
Missing Fate.
Wise Blood!
My Divine Raiment!
You're slow.
Damn it!
Be careful!
Philuffy's Divine Raiment disables other Machine Dragons' Divine Raiments!
All right, then.
I see you're not moving
in the shadows any more.
What's it to you?
Why did you come here?
To bear witness to your majesty's exploits, my princess.
You mean to bear witness to your brother's death.
That sound!
No!
It is!
The orders you give to Abysses and the Ragnarok
through the horn fade after some time, don't they?
So you overrode my orders.
Hayes!
This is the end of the road for you.
If you surrender, we shall spare your life.
This is your final warning.
My final warning?
It seems you are still unaware.
You're the ones who fell for my trap!
Is that what I think it is?!
A Ragnarok!
I brought along a new one,
in order to take control of monster girl over there.
Lisha! We're up against a Ragnarok.
Let's all attack at once!
Got it. Let's do this!
Is that a Ragnarok?
How disappointing.
Wait! Something's not right.
Everyone, dodge!
The nice thing about this one is that its high-speed regeneration strengthens it.
The more damage it receives,
the stronger it gets.
This is bad!
At the rate we'll all—
Miss Lisha, allow me to use it.
That other power hidden within Bahamut.
You mean Over Limit?
No!
Using it is too dangerous!
You're already at your breaking point.
If you push yourself any further, you could...
I can't let this end here!
I don't want to have any more regrets!
All right.
I'll send you the release code from my Tiamat.
Hold out for sixty seconds!
Okay!
Reload on Fire!
Make sure you come back to me, Lux!
I hope you've made your peace, my prince!
I have a question for you.
Do you really want to save
that childhood friend of yours?
Even if you do save her,
nothing is going to change.
You can't protect anything.
You can't do anything.
Your ideals are empty.
End Action!
Fool!
Did you forget that the Ragnarok becomes stronger with every hit you land?!
You haven't changed.
You're just as foolish and weak
as you were back then.
And despite that, I...
Lux!
It's over, you idiot prince playing the hero!
Everyone who idolized you is going to die!
The new kingdom will fall!
And it's all your fault!
No, it's not!
You don't know anything about Lu,
so don't talk to him like that!
You!
What do you know?!
I know.
Lu was always trying to change
this kingdom, even if it hurt him.
I know everything.
Lux, can you hear me?!
I sent you the instructions for
releasing the Machine Dragon!
Use the Over Limit!
So fight!
Not someone else's desires. For yourself, Lu!
Thank you, Phi.
Over Limit On!
That's... Bahamut's true form.
I-Impossible!
Evade it, Ragnarok!
How?!
How could my Ragnarok lose?!
We must retreat, Your Highness.
I still have servants waiting nearby.
I'll get him this—
It's pointless, Hayes.
You can't defeat him, because you don't even see what he's trying to achieve.
What?!
A Ragnarok that becomes ever stronger
can't be defeated even with a Divine Raiment.
That's why he intentionally made it stronger
and used its own strength against it.
Though it's a tactic made possible only by the Over Limit Bahamut.
You truly are my dreadful weakest enemy, Lux.
What in the world happened?!
What have I been doing?!
There's only one thing I can do!
Good night.
Um... aren't you sitting a bit too close?
It's because I'm helping you get better.
Does that really help?
You seem to be feeling better.
Yes. I'm fine as long as I don't strain myself.
Getting used to the horn's sound
helps me fight it.
I see. Glad to hear it.
Say, Lu...
I'm okay now.
Because you kept your promise.
Thank you, Lu.
I love you.
kusaki mo nemuru yoru no sumi de sekai no fushi de
In the nook of night where even trees sleep, in a cranny of the world
neiki ni sotto mimi wo tatete hitomi wo tojiru
I hear the breath of someone asleep nearby,
close my eyes, and prick up my ears
kubisuji ni futto atatakana inochi no tsubu ga
A warm seed of life near my neck
koko ni iru tte sakenderun da koe naki koe de
is screaming that it's there, in a voice without voice
umarekawaretara owarinaki you ni
If we can be reborn endlessly
kimi ga nodo wo itamenakute
Let's take such forms
sumu you na sugata ni narou
that we won't need to scream so hard to be heard
sashiatatte futari tabi doko made arukeru
Now we're traveling, the two of us. How far can we go?
ikeru toko made ikou hohaba awasete
Let's go as far as we can, matching each other's pace
tsukiatatte futari tabi koko made kureba
And when we finally get to the end of the path, the two of us
kigi ni natte tachitsukusou
Let's become trees and stay there
raise ni natte mo zutto koko de nemurou
Even in the next world, let's keep sleeping there
futari nemurou towa ni
The two of us, let's sleep for eternity